DR. MICHELLE COHEN: There is another kind of body language that's very important to remember especially if you're in interviews or trying to make a good impression on someone.
It's called "relaxed and confident body language."
And as in the word relaxed, you are going to show that you are relaxed.
You're not going to be slouching as in boredom or sleepiness.
You're going to be sitting up straight but you're relaxed.
Usually, your legs are not crossed.
You can have maybe your ankles cross behind you.
Open gestures are great like we discussed a little bit earlier.
You have your hand maybe on the side of the chair or on your leg, but you're relaxed.
You're looking at that person and movements are always slow when you're relaxed.
Eye contact is really important, not glaring at someone, just keeping your eyes straight at them.
Gentle smiles are also really important, nodding slowly.
And also when you're trying to express relaxed body, you use your hands like this, gently.
You never use this.
It's always as a matter of fact.
So, you're nodding your head sometimes.
You're looking directly at the person.
Your body is open.
It's relaxed.
And again, you can use this in job interviews, when you're meeting someone for the first time, any kind of new social situation, or on a blind date.
You were really trying to make a good impression and trying to say, "I'm not a nervous person.
I'm not uncomfortable."
These are the things you can do if you are feeling that way.